&gt;&gt; Morning everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家早上好
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
I'm Ross Dexter.
我是 Ross Dexter
I'm an engineer on the Games
我是 Apple 公司游戏技术团队的
Technologies Team at Apple.
一名工程师
And I'd like to welcome you to
欢迎大家来到
going beyond 2D with SpriteKit.
借助 SpriteKit 超越 2D 这个会议
So before we dive in I'd like to
那么在我们正式开始前 我想
quickly talk about what
快速地介绍一下什么是
SpriteKit is and where it fits
SpriteKit 以及如何与
in the Apple rendering picture.
Apple 图形渲染相结合
SpriteKit is Apple's 2D graphics
SpriteKit 是 Apple 为游戏设计的
framework for games.
2D 图形框架
And it's designed to be
其设计的目的就是要实现
flexible, fast, and easy to use.
使用的灵活 快速与便捷
It's supported across all of our
我们所有的平台都支持
platforms and has an Xcode
SpriteKit 并且它有一个
integrated life editor to make
Xcode 集成生命编辑器
lying out and previewing your
使得编排和预览你们的
game content quick and easy.
游戏内容既快速又便捷
SpriteKit sits along SceneKit or
SpriteKit 与 SceneKit 或
other games oriented graphics
其它以游戏为导向的图形
framework and both sit on top of
框架处在同一层 且两者都在
Metal.
Metal 的上层
Traditionally they've all been
传统上 它们都是
used separately in different
在不同的情景下单独
contexts.
使用
SpriteKit for quick and easy 2D,
SpriteKit 可以快速便捷地使用 2D
SceneKit as all ready to use 3D
SceneKit 已经准备充分可以使用
engine, and Metal to give you
3D 引擎 而 Metal 让大家可以
direct access to your devices
直接使用设备的
rendering hardware.
渲染硬件
Instead of keeping all three
与其将它们三个
separate we think it's time that
分开 我们认为现在就是
SpriteKit breaks out of its 2D
让 SpriteKit 打破其 2D 模具的
mold.
时候了
SpriteKit has a great deal to
SpriteKit 功能十分强大
offer to make using it in
结合 SceneKit 和
combination with SceneKit and
Metal 来使用 SpriteKit 极具
Metal attractive.
吸引力
Since they both use Metal under
由于这两者在底层都使用
the hood, it should be trivial
Metal 因此在 SceneKit 中
to render SpriteKit content in
渲染 SpriteKit 的内容
SceneKit or be able to pipe it
或使用任意方式来把它送回
back into Metal use however you
Metal 是轻而易举的
wish.
事情
Lots of 3D games and apps
许多 3D 游戏和 app
feature 2D content and SpriteKit
都使用 2D 的内容 并且 SpriteKit
provides the perfects means for
提供了绝佳的方法来
creating and rendering that
创建和渲染那些
content.
内容
On top of that this year Apple
除此之外 今年 Apple
is introducing ARKit, which
正在推出 ARKit 其将
takes all the hard work out of
创造增强现实 app 的
creating augmented reality apps.
所有难点都解决了
The addition of this new
这一新框架的添加
framework provides one more
提供了另一个原因来说明
reason why it's time for
为什么让 SpriteKit 走出
SpriteKit to go beyond 2D and
2D 并走进第三维度的
into the third dimension.
时候已经到来
And today we're going to show
今天 我们将向大家展示
you how to do it and what you
如何实现这一点以及你们能取得
can achieve.
哪些成就
In this session we're going to
在这个会议中 我们将
cover how to render SpriteKit
涵盖如何在 ARKit 中渲染
content in ARKit, bringing
SpriteKit 内容 从而将
SpriteKit to the world of
SpriteKit 领入增强
augmented reality.
现实的世界
Next, we'll show you how to get
接下来 我们会给大家展示如何
your SpriteKit scenes into
将 SpriteKit 场景放进
SceneKit and how that can
SceneKit 以及这将如何
improve your augmented reality
改善你们的增强现实
apps.
app
And then finally we'll introduce
最后 我们会向大家介绍
you to SKRenderer, which allows
SKRenderer 这能够让大家
you to take more control of how
更好地操控 SpriteKit
SpriteKit updates and renders.
更新和渲染器
All right, let's dive right in
好的 那就让我们一起来
with how you can use SpriteKit
看看如何同时使用
and ARKit together.
SpriteKit 和 ARKit
But first we should talk about
但首先 我们应当谈一谈
what augmented reality actually
增强现实究竟是什么
is. Augmented reality combines a
增强现实将现实世界
real world view with computer
的视图与计算机渲染
rendered content.
内容相结合
That content gets attached to
渲染内容与现实世界中的
locations in the real world so
位置相连接 因此
that as you move your device and
你们在移动设备的时候
the view shifts, the content
视图会有所变化 但内容
appears to remain in place.
似乎还留在原地
That allows you to inspect the
这就使你们可以从不同的
content from different angels as
角度来检查内容 就好像这是
if it were a physical object in
你们的设备面前的一个
front of your device.
实质性物体
And this requires a lot of
这需要进行许多
complex tracking and is a real
复杂的追踪并且实施起来
challenge to implement.
是一个真正的挑战
Thankfully ARKit does all the
多亏了 ARKit 所有艰巨的
hard work for you.
工作都替你们完成了
When you use ARKit it leverages
当你们使用 ARKit 时它会利用
your devices camera,
设备的照相机
accelerometer and other hardware
加速度传感器以及其它硬件设备
to track its position and
来追踪它在现实世界
orientation in the real world.
中的位置和方向
All you have to do is provide it
你们只需要给它提供
the content you want to appear
你们希望在 AR 中出现的
in AR, and ARKit automatically
内容 ARKit 就会随着
updates the relative positioning
设备的移动自动
of your content as your device
更新内容的相应
moves.
定位
If you like a deeper dive into
如果你们想更深入地了解
exactly how this all works, I
这一切究竟是怎么操作的 我
highly recommend checking out
强烈推荐大家去看看
the Introducing ARKit session
本周初举办的介绍 ARKit
that happened earlier this week.
的专题会议
ARKit is able to track and
ARKit 可以追踪并
update the position of your
更新内容的位置
content through the use of
通过使用锚点来
anchors.
实现
They are what make AR work.
正是锚点使得 AR 得以运作
Anchors are 3D points that
锚点是对现实世界的特征
correspond to real world
做出回应的 3D 点
features that ARKit detects
这些特征由 ARKit 通过
through Scene and understanding,
观测和理解来检测出的
which uses your devices camera
也就是使用你们的设备照相机
to perceive and process the
来感知和处理
world around you.
你们周围的世界
Anchors are easy to create.
创建锚点十分容易
You can request ARKit to detect
你们可以通过 API 请求
one at anytime through the API.
ARKit 在任意时间检测一个锚点
Or you can create one manually
或者你们可以利用设备的
using your devices position and
位置和方位手动创建
orientation.
一个锚点
So how do we get ARKit working
那么我们如何让 ARKit 来处理
with SpriteKit content?
SpriteKit 的内容呢
ARKit is designed to interact
设计 ARKit 是为了让它直接
directly with SpriteKit.
与 SpriteKit 交互
ARKit will ask that your -- ask
ARKit 会要求你们的
your first SpriteKit nodes is
SpriteKit 节点
attached to anchors and then
附在锚点上 然后
will automatically position,
就会随着设备的移动
rotate, and scale those nodes as
自动定位 旋转并缩放
the device moves.
这些节点
It does this so your SpriteKit
这样就使得 SpriteKit
content will stay aligned with
内容始终与锚点
the anchors giving the
相一致 看起来
appearance that your content is
就好像这些内容
rooted in the real world.
扎根在现实世界
Sprites are rendered so they are
精灵是渲染出的 因此它们
always facing the camera.
始终面朝照相机
So no matter what angle you view
这样无论你们从哪个角度来
them from they're always facing
浏览它们 它们都总是面朝着
the camera.
照相机
This is a technique known as
这个技术叫做
billboarding and it's commonly
公告牌技术 通常在
used in early 3D games.
早期的 3D 游戏中使用
So you may not be familiar with
大家可能对公告牌技术的
how billboarding works, so let's
运作并不熟悉 那么就让我们
go over a few quick examples of
来快速看几个例子 看看可以
how you can use it, it lets you
如何使用这项技术 它能让你们
use 2D content in 3D space.
在 3D 空间使用 2D 内容
So say we have sprite position
那么假设 我们在 3D 空间中有
in 3D space and a camera
精灵位置还有一个观察
observing it.
它的照相机
As the camera moves closer to
随着照相机离这个精灵
the sprite the sprite grows
越来越近 这个精灵就变得
larger as you'd expect taking
更大 你们在视图中可以看到
more of the view.
精灵占据了更大的空间
As the camera moves further
随着照相机越离越远
away, the sprite shrinks.
这个精灵就缩小了
Now I'll rotate the camera.
下面我将旋转这个照相机
As the camera changes its point
尽管照相机变换了
of view, the sprite continues to
视角 但这个精灵在任何时候都
face the camera at all times.
始终朝向照相机
And this should be the case from
无论我们从哪个角度去看
any angle we view it from.
这一点都是一样的
Let's add another sprite to our
这里 让我们在 3D 场景中
3D scene here to show how this
增加另一个精灵来看看
works with multiple 2D objects.
这将如何与多个 2D 物体一起运作
Sprites that are further away
离照相机更远的精灵
are rendered behind sprites that
被渲染在离照相机更近的
are closer to the camera.
精灵之后
As the camera moves the more
随着照相机的移动 离得
distant sprite comes into view.
更远的精灵进入了视线之中
Both sprites always face the
两个精灵都总是朝向
camera and this simple technique
照相机 这个简单的技术
allows your 2D sprite content to
使得你们的 2D 精灵内容可以
work in a 3D spaces.
在 3D 空间运作
So now that we've shown you how
既然我们已经向大家展示了
ARKit and SpriteKit work
ARKit 和 SpriteKit 如何
together at a conceptual level,
在概念层面共同协作
let's talk about the actual
下面让我们来谈谈
objects you'll need to implement
你们需要在 app 上执行的
your app.
实际对象
To work with ARKit and SpriteKit
要同时使用 Arkit 和 SpriteKit
there are four important objects
你们需要了解四个
for you to know about --
重要的对象 即
ARSession, ARAnchor, ARSKView,
ARSession  ARAnchor  ARSKView
and ARSKViewDelegate.
以及 ARSKViewDelegate
ARSession is the heart of ARKit.
ARSession 是 ARKit 的核心
It handles all the device
它负责处理所有的设备
tracking and orchestrates the
追踪并合理安排
interactions between ARKit and
ARKit 与 SpriteKit 之间的
SpriteKit.
交互
It has methods for adding and
它有方法可以添加并
removing anchors that you create
清除你们在 app 中
in your app.
所创建的锚点
To get started up, you just call
要开始这个过程 你们只需调用
the Run method and ARSession
Run方法 然后 ARSession
will began tracking your device.
便会开始追踪你们的设备
You just need to provide it an
你们只需要向它提供
ARSession Configuration which
ARSession 配置 这可以
tells the ARKit which AR
告诉 ARKit 应该使用
techniques it should use.
哪种增强现实技术
So in working with SpriteKit you
因此 用 SpriteKit 来操作时
should just use the AR World
你们只需要使用 AR 世界
Tracking Session Configuration,
追踪配置
which enables all the
这一配置提供了你们需要
functionality you'll need from
ARKit 提供的所有
ARKit.
功能
ARKit defines real-world
ARKit 通过 ARAnchor 来定义
features through ARAnchor.
现实世界的特征
It represents a position in the
它代表了现实世界的
real world and contains
一个位置并且包含了
transform data as well as a
transform 数据以及一个
unique identifier.
唯一的标识符
ARKit maps ARAnchors to the
ARKit 将 ARAnchors 映射为
SKNodes that we provided to
SKNodes 这是我们提供用于
render our contents.
渲染内容的
ARKit interacts with SpriteKit
ARKit 通过 ARSKView 与 SpriteKit
through ARSKView, which is
进行交互 ARSKView
derived from SKView.
来源于 SKView
It creates and contains the
它创建并包含了
ARSession so you don't need to
ARSession 这样你们就不需要
create it manually.
手动去进行创建
And it has methods for getting
并且它有方法可以获得
related anchors and nodes.
相关的锚点和节点
So you need to manually track
因此 你们需要手动去追踪
which node corresponds to what
哪个节点对应的是哪个
anchor and vise versa.
锚点 反过来也是一样
It also has a hitTest method,
它同时还有 hitTest 方法
which is your primary way of
这是你们创建锚点的
creating anchors.
主要方式
It takes a point on your devices
它需要你们设备屏幕上的
screen and shoots a ray through
一个点并通过这个点射出
it.
一条线
So looking for the nearest point
所以去找找现实世界中离你
in the real world for you to
最近的那个点 把
attach stuff to.
物体附在上面
Finally, there's
最后 来看看
ARSKViewDelegate.
ARSKViewDelegate
A protocol derived from
这是来源于 SKViewDelegate
SKViewDelegate, which helps you
的一个协议 能够帮助你们
react to anchors being added,
对会话控制中添加 更新
updated, and removed from the
以及清除的锚点做出
session.
反应
All of its methods are optional
所有这些方法都是非强制性的
and they're the key to using
它们是同时使用 SpriteKit
SpriteKit and ARKit together.
和 ARKit 的关键
But we'll come back to that in a
但我们一会儿再回到这个
bit.
点来
Let's get started on creating
让我们先来用 SpriteKit
our first ARKit app with
创建我们第一个 ARKit
SpriteKit.
app
First we'll create a new iOS
首先 我们要在 Xcode 里创建
project in Xcode.
一个新的 iOS 项目
You'll see that in Xcode 9,
你们将看到在 Xcode 9 里
there's a new augmented reality
有一个新的增强现实 app
app template for you to choose.
模板供你们选择
Once you choose the app template
你们选择了 app 模板之后
to get started with SpriteKit
要开始使用 SpriteKit
select it as your content
就要选择它作为你们的
technology.
内容技术
And that's all there is to it.
那么现在全部就已经完成了
You're now ready to enter
现在你们可以准备进入
augmented reality.
增强现实世界了
The resulting project looks
对于 iOS app 来说
pretty standard for an iOS app,
最后的项目看上去非常标准化
but let's go through the files
但让我们来看看对于
that are important to using
同时使用 SpriteKit 和 ARKit
SpriteKit and ARKit together.
十分重要的一些文档
First there's Scene.sks.
首先是 Scene.sks
This is a standard SpriteKit
这是一个标准化的 SpriteKit
scene and it's where you create
场景 你们在这里创建
and layout any non-AR content
和布置你们希望出现在
that you want to appear in your
app 上的所有非 AR
app.
内容
It will act like an overlay for
它看上去好像是对 AR
the AR content.
内容的叠加
And so it's useful for things
因此 对于像 HUD 元素
like HUD elements, help text,
帮助文本以及其它类似的内容
stuff like that.
来说是有用的
Nodes that have a Z position
拥有 Z-position 属性并且等于
greater than or equal to 0 will
或大于 0 的节点将
draw over any AR content that
覆盖在 ARKit 添加到场景中的
ARKit adds to the scene.
所有 AR 内容上面
All nodes are managed by -- that
所有的节点都是由
are managed by ARKit have Z
拥有 Z-position 属性且
positions that are less than 0.
小于 0 的 ARKit 管理
Next, Scene.swift.
接下来 看看 Scene.swift
This is a SpriteKit scene's
这是 SpriteKit 场景的一个
corresponding source file.
相对应的源文件
As with normal SpriteKit apps,
就像在普通的 SpriteKit app 中那样
this is where you put code to
你们在这里加入代码来
manage your scene and Gameplay
管理你们的场景 Gameplay
and logic and is a good place to
和逻辑 并且这是一个利用
leverage gameplay kits various
游戏开发工具多种特征的
features.
好地方
And finally we have
最后 让我们来看看
ViewController.swift.
ViewController.swift
The view controller conforms to
视图控制器遵守
ARSKViewDelegate and its
ARSKViewDelegate 并且它的
sceneView property is an
sceneView 属性是
instance of ARSKView, which
ARSKView 的一个实例 其中
contains the ARSession.
包含 ARSession
The view controller class is
视图控制器类是
your primary means of
你们与 ARKit 交互的
interacting with ARKit.
主要方式
In the template it's
在模板中 控制器被
automatically set up to call run
自动设置以通过 AR 世界
on ARSession with an AR World
追踪配置在 ARSession 上
Tracking Session Configuration.
调用 run
So you don't need to add it
这样你们就不需要自行
yourself.
添加了
This is also where you implement
这也是你们执行
the ARSKView Delegate Methods
与你们相关的 ARSKView
that are relevant to you.
代理方法的地方
Now let's talk about the ARKit
下面让我们来谈谈
Events that the view controller
视图控制需要做出
would need to react to.
反应的 ARKit 事件
The first event is when a new
第一个事件就是当新的
anchor gets added to SKSession.
锚点被添加到 SKSession 时
When this happens ARKit will ask
出现这种情况时 ARKit 会请求
the view controller for the
视图控制器提供你们
SpriteKit nodes you want to
希望与锚点相关联的
associate with an anchor.
SpriteKit 节点
So this is when we create our AR
那么这时我们就需要创建
content.
AR 内容
The second event is when an
第二个事件是
existing anchor is updated by
会话控制更新了已有的锚点
the session.
之时
When this occurs ARKit informs a
当发生这一情况时 ARKit 会通知
view controller so you can react
视图控制器 那么你们就可以对
to the update.
更新做出反应
And the third and final event is
第三个也就是最后一个事件是
when an anchor is removed from
当锚点从会话控制中被
the session.
移除之时
ARKit tells the view controller
ARKit 会告知视图控制器
so you can form any necessary
你们就可以对 app 进行
cleanup in your app.
任何必要的清理了
ARSKViewDelegate provides
ARSKViewDelegate 提供了
methods tied to each of these
与每一个事件相关联的
events.
方法
As we mentioned, each of these
我们之前提到过 这些方法中的
methods is optional so you only
每一个都是非强制性的 因此你们
need to implement the ones that
只需执行对你们有用的
matter to you.
那些方法
Let's go over each one.
让我们再回顾一下
First is the node for anchor
首先是锚节点
method.
方法
This gets called when a new
当新的锚点被添加进控制会话时
anchor is added to the session.
就会调用这个方法
An ARKit maps that node return
ARKit 将这个方法
from this method to the anchor
返回的节点映射为
that's passed in.
输入的锚点
You should implement this if you
如果你们想要为锚点创建
want to create a custom node for
一个自定义节点 那么就应该执行
an anchor.
这个方法
If you don't implement the
如果不执行这个
method a default empty SKNode is
方法 那么一个默认的空 SKNode 就会
created for you automatically.
自动为你们创建
The node that gets returned from
这个方法返回的
this method will be moved,
节点将被 ARKit 移动
rotated, and scaled by ARKit to
旋转和缩放从而
match its anchor.
与锚点相匹配
So if you try and make any
所以如果你们尝试对 transform
changes to the transform they'll
进行任何变动
likely be overwritten by ARKit
当设备移动时 这些变动可能
when the device moves.
会被 ARKit 复写
It's useful to know that any
分配给这个节点的
children that are assigned to
任何子节点的 transform 都不会
this node won't have their
被修改 知道这一点是
transforms modified.
很有用的
But we'll talk more about this
我们将在下一个方法中
with our next method.
更多地谈论这点
Also know that ARKit
同时要知道 ARKit
automatically adds this node to
会自动在场景图中
the scene graph so you don't
添加节点 这样你们就不需要
have to.
自行添加了
Next, we have didAdd node for
接下来 我们介绍 didAdd
anchor.
锚节点
This is called after an SKNode
在 SKNode 映射到锚点之后
is mapped to an anchor, so after
可调用这一方法 因此是在
the previous node for anchor
执行了之前的锚节点
method is executed.
方法之后
If you implemented the node for
如果你们执行了锚节点
anchor method, the node that
方法 那么这儿输入的
gets passed in here will be the
节点将会是从那儿
one you returned from there.
返回的那个节点
If you didn't implement it, it
如果你们没执行这个方法 那么
will be a default empty node.
就会有一个默认的空节点
As we mentioned in the previous
正如我们在上一张幻灯片
slide the node that's mapped to
所说的那样 映射到锚点的那个
the anchor has it transformed
节点会让变形的 修改后的
modified ARKit to follow the
ARKit 随着设备的移动
anchor as the device moves.
紧跟着那个锚点
As such, if you want to modify
这样的话 如果你们想要修改
the transforms of your content,
内容的 transform
you should add them as children
你们就应该在此处将它们作为子节点
in here as ARKit won't modify
添加 因为 ARKit 不会对它们
them.
进行修改
Next, we'll update node for
接下来 看看 willUpdate
anchor and didUpdate node for
锚节点以及 didUpdtae 锚
anchor.
节点
These methods are called before
这两个方法是在节点更新了
and after the node is updated
给定的锚点数据之前
with a given anchors data.
以及之后来调用
True to their names willUpdate
正如它们的名字所显示的那样
node for anchor is called before
willUpdate 锚节点在更新
the update, and didUpdate node
之前调用 而 didUpdate 锚
for anchor is called after the
节点则是在更新之后
update.
调用
This occurs when the device
当设备移动以及视图变化时
moves and the view changes.
会发生这一情况
The nodes position, rotation,
这些节点的位置 旋转以及
and or scale is subject to
或者缩放取决于
change between calls to these
调用这些方法之间存在的
methods.
变化
Finally, didRemove node for
最后 来看看 didRemove 锚
anchor.
节点
This gets called the node is
调用这个锚节点是在节点
removed from the scene graph,
从场景图中清除时
which occurs when its course on
当锚点的轨迹从 ARSession
the anchor is removed from
被清除时会发生这一
ARSession.
情况
All right, that covers the
好了 以上便是
important parts of the API.
关于 API 的重要内容
Let's take a look at some code.
下面让我们来看看代码吧
So let's cover creating an
让我们来谈一谈创建
anchor.
锚点
Here we're looking at a handler
这里 我们来看看 touchesBegan
for the touches began event.
事件的处理器
When the device reports a touch,
当设备报告了一个 touch
we get the location of the touch
我们在 ARSKView 中就能获得
in our ARSKView.
touch 的位置
We then provide the touch
然后我们把 touch 的位置
location to the ARSKView's hit
提供给 ARSKView 的 hitTest
test method, which shoots a ray
方法 这个方法会向现实世界
out into the real world looking
射出一道光线来寻找
for feature points that we can
我们可以将之变为锚点的
turn into anchors.
特征点
It returns an array of all the
它会按从近到远的顺序
hits that it registers sorted
返回一道由所有的 hits
from nearest to furthest.
组成的光线
We take the nearest hit and we
我们看到最近的这个 hit 然后
use this world transform to
使用这个 worldTransform
create and ARAnchor, which we
来创建一个 ARAnchor 然后我们
then add to the session.
再添加到会话控制中
And that's all there is to it.
这就是全部内容了
Creating anchors could not be
创建锚点简直简单到
simpler.
不行
So now that we've added a new
那么既然我们已经在会话控制中
anchor to the session, the
添加了新的锚点 会话
session will ask the view
控制将请求视图
controller for the SpriteKit
控制器提供给我们
content that we want to attach
想要附在上面的 SpriteKit
to it.
内容
To do this we've implemented
要做到这一点 我们要执行
ARSKView Delegates didAdd node
ARSKView 代理 didAdd
for anchor method.
锚节点方法
We haven't implemented node for
我们还没有执行锚
anchor, so default empty node
节点 因此就为我们创建了一个
was created for us.
默认的空节点
And that's [inaudible] of this
这就是传递到
method.
这一方法的内容
So now all we need to do is
那么现在我们只需要
create the content we want to
创建我们想要附在锚点
attach to the anchor and then
上面的内容 然后再
add it as a child of the node
把它作为输入这个方法的节点的
that's passed into this method.
子节点添加进去
ARKit will automatically update
ARKit 会自动更新
the node so that it will follow
这一节点使之在设备
the anchor as the device moves
移动时跟随着这个锚点
so you don't need to do anything
这样你们就不需要再做任何
else.
别的事了
So now that we've shown you
那么既然我们已经向大家展示了
exactly how to use the ARKit API
如何通过 SpriteKit 来使用
with SpriteKit, let's enter
ARKit API 就让我们进入
augmented reality.
增强现实的内容
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Let's open our app here.
我们先来打开这里的 app
So we see we're doing our video
我们可以看到我们现在正在
pass through now.
进行视频透传
We can see our lovely audience
我们可以在屏幕上看到我们
out there.
可爱的观众
You're all famous now.
你们现在可都是名人啦
So let's start placing some
下面让我们在增强现实中
content in augmented reality.
放入一些内容
As I tap on my screen I'm
我在点击屏幕的同时
placing content half a meter out
我把内容放在了离我也就半米远
in front of me.
的面前
Here I'm just placing
在这里 我刚用表情符号
SKLabelNode's with Emoji.
添加了 SKLabelNode
Fun fact -- you can use emoji in
有趣的是 你们可以仅通过使用
your SpriteKit apps by just
标签来使用 SpriteKit app
using labels.
里的表情符号
Just paste them in there.
只需把它们粘贴到这里
And you see they have them
你们可以看到它们现在都
floating in 3D space.
悬浮在 3D 空间中
And as I move the camera around
当我四处移动照相机的时候
they move relative to one
它们也移动 但相对位置
another.
不变
Just placing them in space is a
只是把它们放在空间里
little boring.
没什么意思
I can also place them on a
我也可以把它们放在
surface.
平面上
And it will detect intersection
它会检测与平面
with the surface with the
的交集 通过使用我们
HitTest method that we were
刚刚谈到的 HitTest
talking about before.
方法来检测
And then it places the emoji on
然后它会在检测到的
the surface of the table that
桌子平面上放入
it's detected.
表情符号
But placing emoji is just a
但放置表情符号也
little boring.
没什么意思
So now we're going to switch
因此现在我们要转换成
into blasting mode and then we
爆炸模式 然后我们就
can blow up our emoji, which is
可以让我们的表情符号爆炸 这样
a little bit more fun.
才稍微有点意思
Also pay attention to the text
同时 我们要注意我们
in our -- in the lower left hand
此处左下角的文本
corner here and the way that our
以及我们在摧毁表情符号时
emoji are flipping around when
这些表情翻转的
we destroy them, because that's
方式 因为这一点
going to become relevant in a
过一会儿会变得
moment.
有意义
So you see how easy it is to
所以你们可以看到要快速创建
quickly create an app and use a
一个 app 并使用 SpriteKit
SpriteKit content to enter
内容来进入增强现实
augmented realty.
是多么容易
This is just a slightly tweaked
这只是大家现在可以使用
version of the template app that
Xcode 9 创建的 app
you can create right now using
模板稍微调整后的一个
Xcode 9.
版本
And that's SpriteKit with ARKit.
这就是拥有 ARKit 的 SpriteKit
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So you see how easy it is to
那么大家可以看到当把
enter augmented reality when
ARKit 和 SpriteKit 结合起来使用
using ARKit and SpriteKit
的时候 进入增强现实是
together.
多么容易
As I mentioned there are a few
我之前提到过 我们还有
other SpriteKit features in
一些其它的 SpriteKit
there, some of which that were
功能 其中一些在我刚刚
present in the demo that I'd
进行的快速演示中
like to quickly cover.
出现过了
So hopefully you notice the text
所以希望大家有注意到
on the bottom of our screen in
在演示 app 动画里
the demo app animating.
屏幕下方的文本
This was done with a single
这是通过一个单一的
SKLabelNode, thanks to the fact
SKLabelNode 实现的 这是
that they now support attributed
因为它们现在支持属性
strings.
字串符
Attributed strings allows you to
属性字串符使大家可以
specify the attributes of each
指定字符串中每一个字符
character in a string, letting
的属性 这样大家就可以
you mix things like different
把不同的颜色和字体
colors and fonts in the same
混合在同一个
label.
标签中
It uses NSAAttributedString and
它使用了 NSAttributedString
all you have to do is set it on
你们唯一需要做的就是
SKLabelNodes new attributedText
设置 SKLabelNodes 新的 attributedText
property.
属性
The emoji in our augmented
在我们的增强现实
reality apps spun about in ways
app 里的表情符号直到现在
that weren't possible until now
才可以以不可思议的方式旋转
thanks to the new
这都要归功于新的
SKTransformNode.
SKTransformNode
SKNode already had z rotation,
SKNode 已经具备了 Z 旋转的能力
but SKTransformNode adds the
但是 SKTransformNode 为大家
ability for you to rotate around
新增了围绕 X 轴和 Y 轴
the x and y-axis as well.
旋转的能力
Aligned for full 3D rotations
使得 SpriteKit 内容可以进行
for SpriteKit content.
全 3D 旋转
And these rotations apply to all
这些旋转也同样适用于
child nodes as well.
所有的子节点
SKTransformNode uses
SKTransformNode 使用了
orthographic projection.
正交投影
So it doesn't apply any
因此没有对你们的
perspective skewing to your
节点进行任何透视
nodes.
倾斜
You can specify your rotations
你们可以通过 X Y 以及 Z
through the x, y, and z rotation
旋转属性来指定你们的
properties or you can use a
旋转 或者你们可以使用
specialized getters and setters
专门的 getter 和 setter 函数来
for Euler angles, rotation
获得欧拉角 旋转矩阵
matrices, and quaternions.
和四元数
Finally, on the ender side of
最后 在终端的部分
things, SpriteKit is fully
SpriteKit 与 Xcode 的
compatible with Xcode's View
视图调试器完全
Debugger.
兼容
It displays the entire scene
它显示了整个场景
graph and gives you the neat
图并给大家提供了整洁的
exploded 3D view of your scene,
场景 3D 爆炸视图
which can be a great help when
这能够提供极大的帮助 当
you're trying to debug layout --
你们想要去调试排版
content layout issues.
内容排版的问题时
It also allows you to inspect
这同时也让大家可以检查
all of your node properties so
所有的节点属性 这样
you can see the state of
在 app 暂停的那一个瞬间
everything in your scene as the
你们就可以看到场景中的
moment the app was paused.
所有事物的状态
This is a really great new
这真的是一个非常棒的
feature, so please check out the
新功能 所有请大家去看看
debugging with Xcode 9 session
Xcode 9 会议关于调试的内容
for more information on it.
以了解更多信息
We've shown you how quick and
我们已经给大家展示了使用
easy it is to get started with
ARKit 以及 SpriteKit 来
using ARKit and SpriteKit to
创建增强现实的 app
create an augmented reality app.
是多么快速和便捷
ARKit handles all of the hard
ARKit 为大家处理了
parts of augmented reality for
增强现实中所有困难的
you and SpriteKit makes
部分 而 SpriteKit 则让
rendering content a snap.
渲染内容变成小菜一碟
We've also introduced new
我们还介绍了
features to SpriteKit that give
SpriteKit 的新功能 为大家
you greater flexibility in
提供了更大的灵活性来
developing your apps and give
开发 app 并给大家
you new options for debugging
提供调试 SpriteKit 内容的
SpriteKit content.
新选项
But you may have a few lingering
但可能大家还有一些遗留的
questions.
问题
What if we don't want
如果我们并不想要
billboarded sprites?
公告牌精灵呢
What if we want our SpriteKit
如果我们希望通过透视
content to be effective by
来使我们的 SpriteKit 内容
perspective?
生效呢
What if we want to mix 2D and 3D
如果我们想在增强现实中把
content in augmented reality?
2D 和 3D 的内容混在一起呢
What if wanted to take SpriteKit
如果我们想把 SpriteKit 带入
further into 3D?
3D 世界呢
The answer lies in combining
答案就是要把
SceneKit, SpriteKit, and ARKit
SceneKit  SpriteKit 以及 ARKit 这三者
all at once.
全部结合起来
SceneKit and SpriteKit's 3D
SceneKit 是 SpriteKit 的 3D
counterpart, it's a ready to use
版本 这是已经可以使用的
3D engine with it's own Xcode
带有自己的 Xcode 集成现场
integrated live editor.
编辑器的 3D引擎
What you may not know is that
大家可能还有所不知的是
you can use SpriteKit Scenes as
你们可以使用 SpriteKit 场景
the material on geometry in
作为 SceneKit 中几何图形的
SceneKit.
材料
That allows you to render
这使得你们可以用复杂的
SpriteKit content with complex
3D 变换和透视效果
3D transforms and perspective
来渲染 SpriteKit
effect.
内容
Additionally you can easily mix
此外 你们可以轻松地将
2D SpriteKit content with 3D
2D 的 SpriteKit 内容与 3D 的
SceneKit content in the same
ScenenKit 内容混合在同样的
context.
背景中
Like SpriteKit, SceneKit is also
就像 SpriteKit 那样 SceneKit
integrated with ARKit, creating
也同样与 ARKit 相结合在
a project that uses SceneKit in
增强现实 app 中
an augmented reality app is the
使用 SceneKit 创建一个项目 这跟
same as with SpriteKit.
SpriteKit 是一样的
Just change the content
只是把内容技术
technology to SceneKit.
改成 SceneKit 就可以了
The API is designed to be very
这个 API 的设计与大家在
similar to the one you use with
SpriteKit 中所使用的 API
SpriteKit.
非常类似
Only the names of few objects
仅有少数几个对象的名称
are different.
有所不同
ARSKView becomes ARSCNView and
ARSKView 变成了 ARSCNView 而
ARSKViewDelegate becomes
ARSKViewDelegate 变成了
ARSCNViewDelegate.
ARSCNViewDelegate
As with SpriteKit the template
在 SpriteKit 中 模板会为
creates ARSCNView for you and
大家创建 ARSCNView 同时
the ViewController conforms to
视图控制器遵守
ARSCNViewDelegate.
ARSCNViewDelegate
Now in the interest in brevity
现在 为了节约时间
and because the API is so
也因为 API 非常类似
similar, we won't bother
所以在这里我们就不再
covering the rest here.
介绍剩余的内容了
So next we want to get out
那么下面 我们想在 SceneKit
SpriteKit content rendering
的场景中渲染
within a SceneKit scene.
SpriteKit 的内容
Normally with SpriteKit you have
通常 在 SpriteKit 中 你们有
your scene and you set it on an
场景并且你们把它设置在
SKView.
SKView 上
SKView then works with UIKit or
然后 SKView 与 UIKit 或
AppKit on Mac OS to get your
Mac OS 的 AppKit 共同把你们的
content on screen.
内容放到屏幕上
To get your content rendering in
为了使你们的内容在 SceneKit
SceneKit things are handled a
里渲染 处理的方式
little differently.
略有不同
Instead of setting your scene on
现在不用将场景设置在
the view, you set it on the
视图上 而是设置在
material property of the
你们希望出现 SpriteKit
geometry on which you want the
内容的几何图形的
SpriteKit content to appear.
材料属性上
And then that material works
然后这个材料与 SceneKit
with SceneKit to render you
一起来渲染
SpriteKit content and then
SpriteKit 的内容 然后
texture map it onto the geometry
纹理将之映射在
the material is associated with.
与材料相关联的几何图形中
So let's go over a few examples
下面 让我们来看几个
of rendering SpriteKit content
在 SceneKit 几何图形中渲染
on SceneKit Geometry.
SpriteKit 内容的例子
Here was have a basic SpriteKit
这里 我们有一个基本的 SpriteKit
scene.
场景
And here's what we get when we
那么这个就是当我们在 SceneKit
render that on a scene on a
的平面渲染这个场景
plane in scene kit.
时会看到的
We also apply the SpriteKit's
我们还可以把 SpriteKit 的
scene to a cube or even a
场景应用到立方体甚至是
sphere.
球体中
You can use it just like a
你们可以把它当成
regular texture and the
普通纹理那样来使用
SpriteKit -- as the SpriteKit
而 SpriteKit 随着 SpriteKit
scene updates, your texture will
场景的更新 你们的纹理会
be updated along with it.
随之一同更新
So now I'd like to quickly show
那么现在 我想快速地向大家
you how easy it is to use
展示用 SceneKit 来使用
SpriteKit with SceneKit.
SpriteKit 是多么容易
First, get the SpriteKit scene
首先 在 SceneKit 中获取
that you want to use in
一个你们想要使用的
SceneKit.
SpriteKit 场景
Next, create the geometry you
接下来 创建你们想要
want the SpriteKit scene to be
用来渲染 SpriteKit 场景的
rendered on.
几何图形
Here we're creating a simple
这里我们创建了一个简单的
plane.
平面
Then you just need to set the
然后你们只需要把 SpriteKit
SpriteKit scene as the contents
场景设置为平面
of the diffuse property of the
材料中漫反射属性的
planes material.
内容
That will cause the SceneKit to
这会导致 SceneKit 将
render the SpriteKit Scene to a
SpriteKit 的场景渲染成一个
texture and then apply it to the
纹理然后再把它应用到
geometry.
几何图形上
Here we're setting the material
在这儿我们把材料
to be double-sided.
设置成双面的
This causes the SpriteKit Scene
这就使得 SpriteKit 的场景
to appear on both sides of the
在平面的两侧
plane.
同时出现
Then we just need to create a
接下来我们就只需为这个平面
SceneKit node for the plane and
创建一个 SceneKit 节点 然后
add it to the SceneKit scene.
把它添加到 SceneKit 场景中
Now the plane will show up in
现在这个平面将出现在
the scene with the contents of
这个场景中并带有你们
your SpriteKit scene texture
在上面映射的 SpriteKit 场景
mapped onto it.
纹理的内容
So now I'd like to show you demo
那么下面我想给大家做一个演示
of some of the things you can do
看看你们在使用 SpriteKit 和
when you use SpriteKit and
SceneKit 时结合 ARKit
SceneKit together with ARKit.
可以做些什么
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
All right.
好的
So here I have a demo that I've
在这里我有一个在 ARKit
built on top of the sample code
发布的样本代码基础上
that ARKit has released, that
建立的演示
you can find to their session
你们可以在关于这一内容的
website.
网站上找到
And here I just is detecting a
那么现在我在检测
plane for us.
一个平面
Now if I tap on the screen it
如果我点击屏幕
places a SpriteKit scene for us
那么它就会在这里的世界
in the world here.
为我们创建一个 SpriteKit 场景
And you see that this a fully
你们可以看到这是一个全
live SpriteKit scene.
动态的 SpriteKit 场景
You see the trees are animating.
你们可以看到这些树在活动
And in fact I can actually
事实上 我可以直接
interact with this directly.
跟它进行交互
Well, here let's actually --
让我们真正地来
let's blow it up a little bit.
让我们稍微放大一点
Since we are in 3D we can do all
由于我们处在 3D 空间中 我们可以
kinds of cool things.
做所有酷炫的事情
We can move this guy around, we
我们可以把它移来移去 我们
can rotate, and we can scale,
可以旋转 我们还可以缩放
make it a little bigger.
把它稍微变大点
So now I can actually interact
所以现在我可以直接同
with this scene directly.
这个场景交互了
I have controls on my device
我可以控制这儿的
here, I can move my character
设备 我可以移动我的
around, you can jump around.
这个小人 让它四处跳动
Hard to get over that thing.
跳过它还有点难呢
Yeah. And so we can jump around
好了 我们可以四处跳动
in real time, interact with this
与它进行实时的交互
just like a normal SpriteKit
就跟普通的在 3D 中渲染的
scene rendered in 3D.
SpriteKi 场景一样
But just having it sit here on
但只是让它呆在
the surface is a little boring.
平面上没什么意思
We should do something a little
我们应该做些稍微更
more interesting, it a little
有趣的事情 让它更
more 3D.
3D 一点
So if I actually touch this
所以如果我点击这里的
button up here, the scene flips
按钮 这个场景就会向上
up and --
弹起
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
If I touch it again it separates
如果我再点击一下 它就会
the different layers that I have
在这里分出不同的
in here.
几层
So we don't actually have just
因此我们实际上不止有
one SpriteKit scene --
一个 SpriteKit 场景
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
We actually have three
在这里我们实际上有三个
SpriteKit's scenes here, one for
SpriteKit 场景 这里的每一层
each layer here.
都有一个
One for the middle -- front,
前面有一个
middle, and background.
中间和后面各有一个
So this shows you the kind of
这就给大家展示了
stuff that you can do when you
你们在使用 SpriteKit
use SpriteKit and SceneKit
和 SceneKit 时结合 ARKit
together with ARKit but maybe
可以做些什么 但可能
you start to feel a little
你们开始觉得有点
constrained by the level here.
受到级别的限制了
And maybe we want to have our
或许我们想要自己的这个
little guy go out on an
小人走出来去自己
adventure on his own.
开启一场探险
He can run out into the real
它可以进入真实的
world here.
世界
Oh this button looks kind of
这个按钮看着让人相当
tempting.
想按下去
Yay.
太棒啦
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So that gives you an idea of
那么这就让大家明白了
what you can do when you use
在 3D 背景里同时使用
SpriteKit in a 3D context with
SpriteKit  SceneKit  ARKit
SceneKit together with ARKit.
可以做些什么了
So as you saw using SpriteKit
大家可以看到 结合 SceneKit
with SceneKit allows for full 3D
使用 SpriteKit 可以实现
transforms and perspective,
全 3D 变换和透视
which allows you to do some
这又让大家可以做些
pretty neat things.
很酷的事情
It allows you to mix 2D and 3D
它让大家可以把 2D 和 3D 的
content within the same context
内容混合在同一个背景中
and it's fully compatible with
并且与 ARKit 完全
the ARKit and it works great in
兼容 同时它在普通的 3D
general 3D apps as well.
app 中也可以很好地操作
So now that we've covered how to
刚才我们已经谈到了如何
work with ARKit and SceneKit, I
使用 ARKit 和 SceneKit 下面
would like to introduce you to a
我们向大家介绍 SpriteKit
another new SpriteKit feature --
的另一个新功能
SKRenderer.
SKRenderer
Let's talk a bit about how
让我们来稍微看看
SpriteKit works under the hood.
SpriteKit 在底层是怎么运行的
As we've mentioned in the
我们在上一个板块中
previous section, with normal
已经提到了 使用普通的
SpriteKit Rendering you have
SpriteKit 渲染 你们有
your scene and you set it on an
自己的场景并把它设置在
SKView, which then works with
SKView 上 然后再同
UIKit and AppKit to get your
UIKit 和 AppKit 一起来把你们的
content on the screen.
内容放在屏幕上
SKView handles all of the
SKView 会为你们处理
updating and rendering for you.
所有的更新和渲染
The upside of this is that it
这一点的好处是它使得
makes it very easy to get
用 SpriteKit 来起步
started with SpriteKit.
非常容易
But what if you want to render
但如果你们想要在一个
SpriteKit content in a 3D
3D 背景里渲染 SpriteKit
context?
内容呢
One solution as we showed you is
解决方法就像我给大家展示的那样
to use SpriteKit with SceneKit.
结合 SceneKit 来使用 SpriteKit
Instead of setting your scene on
不用把场景设置在
the view, you use it as a
视图上 你们可以把它用作
material in SceneKit.
SceneKit 的材料
And this let's you do all kinds
并且这能让大家做一切
of cool stuff.
酷炫的事情
But when SpriteKit updates and
但当 SpriteKit 的更新和
renders is still out of your
渲染仍不受你们操控
hands.
时
What if you want more control?
如果你们想要更多的控制呢
Maybe you want to update with
或许你们想要按照具体的固定的
exact fixed time steps or update
时间步骤来更新或是不加
without rendering or render
渲染地更新或是不加
without updating or update once
更新的渲染又或是更新一次
and render twice, each time from
渲染两次 每次都从不同的
a different viewpoint.
视角进行
What if we wanted to work
如果我们想要直接和 Metal
directly with Metal?
一起使用呢
Enter SKRenderer.
那就进入 SKRenderer
You use it instead of SKView to
你们可以使用 SKRenderer 而不是
gain more control over
SKView 来更多地操控
SpriteKit.
SpriteKit
Like SKView, to use it you just
就像 SKView 要使用 SKRenderer
set it your scene -- you set
你们只需要把你们的
your scene on it on the
场景设置在
renderer.
渲染器上
Unlike SKView however,
但与 SKView 不同的是
SKRenderer let's you determine
SKRenderer 让你们来决定
when SpriteKit performs updating
SpriteKit 什么时候进行更新
and rendering.
和渲染
It allows you to work directly
它让大家可以直接通过
with Metal and then you can do
Metal 运作 然后你们就可以
things like render SpriteKit
把 SpriteKit 渲染成
into an off screen texture to
一个纹理然后
use however you want.
随心所欲地使用了
This by the way is how SceneKit
这正是 SceneKit
is able to efficiently render
能够在 3D 背景中有效
SpriteKit content in 3D.
渲染 SpriteKit 内容的方式
It uses SKRenderer under the
它在底层使用了
hood.
SKRenderer
There are four stages to using
使用 SKRenderer 一共有
SKRenderer -- initialization,
四个步骤 初始化
setting the scene, updating, and
设置场景 更新以及
rendering.
渲染
Initialization occurs once.
初始化只出现一次
You set your scene at the start
在一开始就要进行场景设置
and again we want the transition
如果要转换新的场景则要
to a new scene and update and
再次设置 而更新和
renderer repeat every frame in
渲染在 app 的每一帧都要
your app.
重复进行
Let's look at some code for each
让我们来看看每一个步骤
of these stages.
的代码
Stage one Initialization.
第一步 初始化
To initialize SKRenderer, all
要将 SKRenderer 初始化
you need to do is provide it
你们只需要向它提供
with a Metal device.
一个 Metal 设备
Stage Two, setting the scene.
第二步 设置场景
This works exactly the same as
这与 SKView 的做法是
with SKView, just that your
完全相同的 只需要
scene on SKRenderer's scene
把场景设置在 SKRenderer 的场景
property.
属性上
Stage Three, updating.
第三步 更新
Also very simple, all you need
这同样非常简单 你们
to do is pass in the current
只需要输入
time.
currentTime
Stage four, rendering.
第四步 渲染
This is done by calling the
这可以通过调用渲染
render method of which there are
方法来完成 具体方式
two flavors.
有两种
Which one you want to use is
你们想采用哪种方式
situational, depending on how
取决于你们想
you want to use your SpriteKit
怎样结合 Metal 来使用你们的
content with Metal.
SpriteKit 内容
Both methods ask you to specify
两个方法都要求大家指定
your viewport you like to render
你们想要渲染的
into, which is just the CGrect
视口 也就是 CGrect
that defines the area of
定义了在渲染目标里
SpriteKit will draw into in the
SpriteKit 将要绘制的
render target.
区域
And they both take a Metal
两种方法都有 Metal
render pass descriptor, which
渲染通过描述符 这
describes that render target
描述了你们希望 SpriteKit
that you want the SpriteKit
内容绘制的
content to draw into.
渲染目标
Now the first method allows you
第一个方法让你们可以
to specify the command buffer to
指定 SpriteKit 来创建
which SpriteKit will schedule
渲染命令的
rendering commands.
命令缓冲区
A good case in which to call
调用这一方法的一个
this method is if you're not
很好的案例是如果你们没有
directly mixing SpriteKit
直接把 SpriteKit 内容与
content with other Metal content
其它的 Metal 内容混合在
in the same render target.
同一个渲染目标里
If you want to render a
如果你们想把一个
SpriteKit scene into a texture
SpriteKit 场景渲染成纹理
and then apply it through some
然后再通过一些 3D 几何图形
3D geometry like we did in the
进行应用 就像我们给大家
second demo we showed you this
做的第二个演示那样 那么
is the method you'd want to
你们可能会想要调用这个
call.
方法
The second method gives you more
第二个方法给了大家更多的
granularity by allowing you to
粒度 让大家可以
direct which render command
决定 SpriteKit 的渲染命令
encoder SpriteKit will encode
将在哪个渲染命令编码器
its render commands.
上进行编码
This is good if you want to
如果你们想直接
directly mix SpriteKit and metal
把 SpriteKit 和 Metal 的内容混在
content in the same render
相同的渲染目标中 那么这种方式
target.
是适用的
So you want to render some 2D
所以你们想要和 SpriteKit
Metal content along with your
内容一道渲染一些 2D 的
SpriteKit content or maybe you
Metal 内容 或许你们想要
want to overlay SpriteKit on top
在 Metal 场景上叠加
of a Metal scene to display HUD
SpriteKit 来显示 HUD
elements.
元素
By using the same render command
通过使用相同的渲染命令
and coder, you can do this much
及编码器 你们可以大大地提高
more efficiently than if you
效率 超过你们使用
were using the first method.
第一个方法的效率
All right, that's enough of an
好了 这就是 API
API crawl.
的内容了
Let's jump into a quick demo
让我们来快速做一个演示
showing SpriteKit rendering in
看看如何在 3D 中用 Metal 进行
3D with Metal.
SpriteKit 渲染
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
SO here we have a 3D scene in
在这里，我们有一个 Metal 的
Metal.
3D 场景
See we've got some nice lighting
你们看 在这儿我们有明亮
and some shadows going on here
的光线还有一些阴影
and we have this very tempting
我们还有这台非常吸引人的
looking arcade cabinet with our
街机 上面还带有
beautiful SpriteKit framework
漂亮的 SpriteKit 框架
logo on it.
标识
We walk up to it, Insert Coin,
让我们朝着它走过去“插入游戏币”
that sounds like of tempting.
听上去也相当吸引人
I've got a quarter here.
我有个硬币
Let's plop that baby in.
让我们把它插进去
Oh, you see we've got a full
你们看 我们就得到了一个
SpriteKit scene rendering on
在这个 3D Metal 场景上渲染的
this 3D Metal scene.
SpriteKit 场景
And see we're using SKRenderer
看 我们在使用 SKRenderer
to render SpriteKit into a
将 SpriteKit 渲染成一个
texture, which we're then
纹理 然后我们
mapping onto the front of our
再把它映射到这里的
arcade cabinet here.
街机前
And then we're just applying a
接下来我们只需要把一个
cool CRT shader to an in Metal
CRT 着色器应用到 Metal 中
to give it this old school look.
以获得这种复古学院派的外观
I can actually move around from
实际上 我可以随心所欲地从
any angle I want to here and I
任意角度移动 我还可以
can interact with it like this.
像这样跟它交互
It's a little bit of askew, but
这稍微有点歪
you know, maybe this gives you
但或许这让大家
some memories of playing on an
回想起了曾经跟朋友
arcade cabinet with your
一起玩街机的时候
friends, you're all crowded up
你们都互相挤在一起
against it.
来玩游戏
And you can view this from any
你们可以从任意角度来
angle, you can view this all
视图 你们可以从远处
from a distance, and it shows
来视图 它会向你们显示出
you some of the things that you
一些你们结合 Metal
can do with SpriteKit when you
使用 SpriteKid 能做的
use it with Metal.
一些东西
It let's you use it 3D and then
它让你们可以在 3D 中使用
you can do whatever you want
然后你们可以随意处理
with that texture.
这个纹理
So that's SpriteKit and Metal
以上就是 SpriteKit 和 Metal
working together.
一起操作的内容
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
SKRenderer gives you more
SKRenderer 让大家能够对
control over SpriteKit than ever
SpriteKit 进行前所未有的
before.
操控
It allows you to determine
它让你们可以决定
exactly when it updates and
具体什么时候更新和
renders and by interacting
渲染 并且通过直接
directly with Metal you can use
与 Metal 交互 你们可以把
rendered SpriteKit content
渲染的 SpriteKit 内容用在任何
anyway you see fit.
你们觉得合适的地方
As you've seen today SpriteKit
今天大家已经看到了 SpriteKit
is useful in both 2D and 3D.
对 2D 和 3D 都适用
It's built to work well with
它也能够同诸如 SceneKit
other graphics frameworks like
和 Metal 这样的其它图形框架
SceneKit and Metal.
一起使用
And it's closely integrated with
并且 SpriteKit 与 ARKit 紧密
ARKit, so that creating
结合 因此创建
augmented reality apps is as
增强现实 app
easy as possible.
变得极其简单
We've introduced new features
我们介绍了新的特征
that give you more control than
给大家提供了前所未有的操控性
ever allowing you to view
让大家可以在视图调试器
SpriteKit content in the View
中来浏览 SpriteKit 内容
Debugger and also giving you the
还让你们可以
ability to take direct control
直接控制何时及
over when and how SpriteKit
以何种方式来结合新的
updates and renders with a new
SKRenderer 进行 SpriteKit 的更新
SKRenderer.
和渲染
Today we've shown SpriteKit in
今天 我们展示了 SpriteKit
an entirely new light and we
的全新面貌 我们
hope that it's given you some
希望这能给大家带来一些
perspective on how you can use
启发 去思索如何以
it in ways that you may have
你们意想不到的方式
never thought of before.
来进行使用
So for information and access to
关于这场会议的更多信息及
this session video please visit
视频 请访问
developer.apple.com/wwdc17/609.
developer.apple.com/wwdc17/609 这个网站
And please check out these
也请关注其它相关的
related sessions.
会议
We gave just a small taste of
在今天的发布会上 我们仅
metal in today's section.
涉及到了 Metal 的小部分内容
So please check out Introducing
如果你们想要了解更多
Metal 2 if you're interested in
请关注 Metal 2 介绍这一
learning more.
会议
I highly recommend watching
我强烈建议大家观看
"Introducing ARKit" to learn
“ARKit 介绍”来了解
more about how it works in
关于操作的详细
detail.
信息
And if our quick look at
如果我们对 SceneKit 的
SceneKit got your attention you
快速讲解引起了大家的兴趣
should look at their main
你们可以看看今年的
session this year.
主要会议
And there's a lot of great stuff
“用 Xcode 9 调试”这个专会议
in the Debugging with Xcode 9 on
上也有很多精彩的内容
top of SpriteKit working with a
比如在 SpriteKit 上用新的视图
new View Debugger.
调试器进行调试
Like wireless debugging which is
比如非常强大的
really awesome, so I recommend
无线调试 所以我建议大家
watching that as well.
也去看看这场
Thanks everyone and please enjoy
感谢大家 希望大家愉快地度过
the rest of the conference.
接下来的会议